'메이시 백화점
추수감사절 퍼레이드'
자기야, 접시 내리는것 좀
도와줄래?
Hey, hon? Would you help me
get the plates down?
우리 결혼할때 산
그릇 쓰는게 어때?
Hey, here's an idea. Why don't
we use our wedding china today?
그건 아껴뒀다가
아주 특별한 날 쓸거야
Or we could save them
for a fancy special occasion.
그럼 이건 어때?
날 진지하게 받아주던가
How about this:
You could treat me like I'm an equal..
아니면 날 내려다보면서
아이 취급하던가
or talk down to me
like I'm a child.
그게 아니라, 좀더
특별한 날에 쓰고 싶어서
No, I just think we should save our china
for something really special.
영국 여왕이 오신다던가..
Like if the queen of England
comes over.
초대해도 번번이 취소하잖아
그정도면 눈치채야지
Honey, she keeps canceling on us.
Take the hint.
깨지면 어떡해!
얼마나 비싼건데!
What if something breaks?
They're expensive.
쓰지도 않을 거면서
가지고 있으면 뭘해
What is the point of having them
if we never use them?
만약 그릇 깨졌는데
여왕이라도 오시면..
Okay. But if something breaks
and then the queen comes over..
내가 잘 설명할게
- I will explain it to her.
- Like I'd let you talk to the queen.
내가 자기한테 여왕과
말할 기회 줄것 같아?
올해 퍼레이드
진짜 근사하다!
Wow, the parade is really good this year.
저 말은 똥도 싸겠는데!
Man, those horses can crap.
다음은 오클라호마 머스코기의
고적대입니다!
Next up is a marching band
from Muskogee, Oklahoma.
머스코기?
털사에서 4시간 떨어진 곳이야!
Muskogee?
That's like four hours from Tulsa!
'모다' 멋져요!
Y'all look great!
그래, 나도 이젠 '모다'라고 한다!
That's right, I said "y'all!"
인기 드라마
"우리 인생의 나날들"출연진이
Here's the float with the stars
of the popular daytime soap..
풍선과 함께 행진합니다!
Days of Our Lives.
엄마야!
Oh, my God!
너 저 인기 드라마
출연진 아니었니?
Aren't you one of the stars of the
popular daytime soap Days of our Lives?
깜박했다!
나 저기 가야하는데!
I forgot! I'm supposed to be there!
저걸 왜 까먹었지?
중요한건 꼭 팔에 적어놓는데!
I can't believe I forgot! I usually write
stuff like this down on my arm!
소매가 왜 이렇게 긴거야!
Stupid long sleeves!
- 어떡할거야?
- 저기 못간 그럴듯한
- What are you gonna do?
- I'll come up with a good reason..
이유를 대야지
why I wasn't there.
PD가 무지 화낼거야
어제 다 모아놓고 그랬거든
The producers are gonna be mad.
They sat us down and said:
"전원, 오전 6시까지 집합!
조이, 자네한테 하는 말이야!"
"Everyone has to be there, 6 a.m. sharp.
That means you, Tribbiani."
날 아주 바보 취급하더라니까
Like I was some kind of idiot.
- 아니란걸 증명했잖아
- 맞아
Well, you proved them wrong.
프렌즈 시즌 9
'서열 정하기'
엠마?
Oh, Emma.
네 첫번째 추수감사절이구나
This is your first Thanksgiving.
뭘 감사할래?
What are you thankful for?
엄마 찌찌?
Mommy's boobies?
많은 사람들이 거기에 대해
감사하곤 하지
A lot of people are thankful for those.
레이첼?
Hello? Rachel?
누구세요?
Who is it?
언니가 사랑하는 동생!
It's your favorite sister.
- 질?
- 에이미야!
- Jill?
- Amy!
내 반지들 숨겨줘!
Hide my rings.
에이미!
해피 추수감사절!
Amy! Happy Thanksgiving.
머리 펴는 고데기 있어?
Do you have a hair straightener?
어.. 안녕?
Hi.
안녕
- Hi.
머리 펴는거 있어?
Hair straightener.
- 우리 못본지 1년쯤 됐나?
- 그래, 정신없이 바빴어
- I haven't seen you in, like, a year.
- I know. I know. I've just been crazed.
나도 그래
난 아기 낳았어
Well, me too. I had a baby.
난 아빠 사무실
인테리어 했어
I decorated Dad's office.
뱃속에서 책상 밀어냈다면 모를까
나랑은 차원이 다르지
Yeah? Well, unless you pushed a desk
out of your vagina, not the same thing.
머리 펴는거 말야, 나 급해
About that hair straightener,
honey, I really need one.
남자친구 집에서 저녁 먹거든
I'm gonna have dinner
at my boyfriend's house.
- 어머나!
- 그래
Oh, my God.
얘가 에밋이야?
Is this Emmett?
엠마야
It's Emma.
딸이었어?
It's a girl?
- 안녕, 에이미?
- 로스 기억하지?
- Hey, Amy.
- Amy, you remember Ross?
모르겠는데
Not really.
언니가 전에 사귀던
남자보다 훨씬 낫네요
But you are much cuter
than that geeky guy she used to date.
그게 나였어
That was me.
아뇨, 그 남자는
중학교때 부턴가
No, he was this creepy guy from high
school who had this huge crush on her..
언니 쫓아다닌 진드기였어요
since, like, the ninth grade.
그것도 나야
Still me.
아니래두요
No, I'm not talking about you.
그 남자는 언니 뚱보친구 오빠고
둥근 흑인머리 했었잖아?
It was your fat friend's brother
with that bad Afro.
에이미, 내가 수고를 덜어줄게
그게 나라구!
Okay, Amy, I'm gonna save you
some time, okay? All me!
조심해
Careful. Careful.
조심해!
Careful!
죽는 날까지 조심할게
I'll tell you what.
For the rest of our lives..
그말 그만 할때까지
I'll be careful until told otherwise.
잠깐, 이건 우리가
골랐던 그릇 아니잖아?
- This isn't the china we picked out.
- I know.
자기가 가게 나가자마자
내가 다른걸로 바꿨어
After you left the store,
I chose different ones.
- 왜?
- 자기가 고른건 좀 여성스럽더라구
- Why?
- Your taste is a little feminine for me.
꽃무늬가 언제부터
여성취향이었어?
Suddenly flowers are feminine?
안녕, 해피 추수감사절!
Hey, everybody! Happy Thanksgiving!
- 어서와! 피비, 나좀 봐
- 무슨 일인데?
- Happy Thanksgiving. Phoebe!
- What's going on, Joe?
좋은 거짓말거리 없을까?
Listen, I need a good lie.
그래?
Okay.
인간이 달을
걷는다는건 어때?
How about the whole "man walking
on the moon" thing, you know?
사람들은 피아노 줄이
안보이나봐!
You can see the strings, people!
아니, 오늘일 안나간거
핑계댈만한 거짓말이 필요해
No, no, no. I need a good lie to explain
why I wasn't at a work thing today.
- 너 거짓말 젬병이잖아
- 아냐
- Honey, you stink at lying.
- I do not.
그럼 하나 물어볼게
어제 카페에서
Really? Let me ask you something.
Yesterday at the coffeehouse..
화장실 다녀오니까
내 머핀이 없어졌어, 누구 짓이지?
I went to the bathroom. When I came
back, my muffin was gone. Who took it?
누가 카페 문을 여니까
Somebody opened the door
to the coffeehouse..
너구리가 들어와
네 머핀 쪽으로 가더라구
and a raccoon ran in and went
straight for your muffin. I said:
"먹지마! 그건 피비거야!"라고
했더니 너구리 왈..
"Hey, don't eat that!
That's Phoebe's!" And he said..
"조이, 넌 거짓말 젬병이구나"
나 어떡하지?
He said, "Joey, you stink at lying."
What am I gonna do?
걱정마, 내가 좋은 핑계거리
생각해서 연습까지 시켜줄게
Don't worry. We'll come up with a lie.
I'll help you.
- 그러면야 좋지! 고마워!
- 그런데 무슨 일이었는데?
- Great. That'd be great. Thank you.
- Sure. What was the work thing?
- "공항으로 할머니 마중"?
- 으! 큰일났다!
- "Pick up Grandma at the airport."
- Oh, man!
아기 예쁘다
She's precious.
언니 수술전 코를 닮으면
어쩌나 걱정 안돼?
Do you ever worry
that she's gonna get your real nose?
에이미?
Amy..
실은 많이 걱정돼
Yes, I do. I really do.
여보세요?
Hello?
잠깐만
위층가서 받아도 돼?
Yeah, hang on, one sec.
Can I take this upstairs?
그럼, 우리집은 아니지만..
Sure. We don't live there, but..
정말? 집이 이게 다야?
Seriously? It's just these rooms?
- 의사 아니었어요?
- 로스는 고생물학 박사야
- I thought you were a doctor.
- Yeah. No, Ross has a Ph.D.
정말 감당 안되는 애야!
God, she is unbelievable.
글쎄 말야!
박사도 의사만큼 훌륭하다구!
I know. I mean, a Ph.D.
is just as good as an MD.
암, 그렇구말구
Sure, Ross, yeah!
만약 나 심장마비 걸리면
화석발굴용 붓으로 처치해줘
If I have a heart attack at a restaurant,
I want you there with your fossil brush.
- 거지같은 추수감사절!
- 왜?
- Stupid Thanksgiving.
- What?
- 무슨 일인데?
- 남자친구가 약속 깼어!
- What? What happened?
- My boyfriend canceled on me.
마침내 명절을 함께 지낼
제대로된 남자를 만났는데
I mean, I finally find a real relationship.
하필 이럴때 그 남자 부인이
돌아올게 뭐람!
Someone that I can spend this day with,
and then his wife comes back into town!
유부남이랑은 별로 사귈게
못되는것 같아!
I swear, it's almost not even
worth dating married guys.
그럴리가!
Don't say that.
오늘을 얼마나 기다렸는데
God, I was so looking forward to this.
환상적인 추수감사절을
보낼 계획이었다구
It was gonna be such
a beautiful Thanksgiving.
초밥 먹으려고 했단 말야
We were gonna have sushi.
에이미, 울지마
Amy, don't cry.
- 로스, 얘기좀 할래?
- 좋아, 위층으로 올라갈까?
- Ross, can I talk to you in private?
- Sure, you wanna go upstairs, or..?
모니카만 괜찮다면
Look, I was thinking,
if it's okay with Monica..
오늘 추수감사절 만찬에
에이미도 초대하면 좋겠어
I would like to invite Amy
to Thanksgiving.
그거 좋은 생각이다!
미국 최초 이주자들이 인디언한테
I think that's a great idea. It'll be like
the Pilgrims bringing the Indians syphilis.
성병 옮기는것 같겠네!
봐주기 힘든 애란거 알아
Look, I know she's a little tough to take.
하지만 갈데도 없고
내 동생인걸, 엠마와 이모가
But she has nowhere else to go,
and she's my sister. She's Emma's aunt.
친해질수 있는 기회잖아
- And I would like them to bond.
- I don't want them bonding too much.
좋아, 하지만 둘이 너무
친해지는건 싫어
나중에 엠마한테 코수술
해야겠다고 하면 어떡해!
I don't want her telling Emma
she needs a nose job.
정말 해야할지도 몰라!
현실을 인정하자구!
Ross, she may need one. We're just
gonna have to make our peace with that!
에이미..
Amy..
에이미?
Amy?
에이미!
Amy!
밖에 있어
I'm out in the hall.
언니 애가
괴상한 냄새를 풍겨서
Your baby had some sort of
explosion of stink.
정말 많이 친해진거 같아
The bonding's going great.
- 안녕?
- 어서와
- Hi!
- Hey.
내 동생 에이미야
Hey, you guys. This is my sister, Amy.
챈들러, 조이 그리고 피비야
모니카는 알지?
This is Chandler, Joey,
Phoebe, and you know Mon.
어머!
Oh, my God.
우리 인생의 나날들에
나오는 사람이죠?
You're on Days of Our Lives!
네
Yeah.
우와!
순전히 화장발이었구나!
Wow! They must put
a lot of makeup on you.
해피 추수감사절..
Happy Thanksgiving.
- 안녕
- 어서와
- Hey.
- Hi.
잘왔어
엠마 처음 보는거지?
So welcome. Is this the first time
you're seeing Emma?
그럴걸요?
만나서 반가워요, 엠마
Yeah, I think so.
It's nice to meet you, Emma.
- 피비
- 어머, 재미있는 소리네요
- Phoebe.
- That's a funny noise.
- 피비, 나 도와준댔잖아
- 그래, 알았어
- Phoebe? I still need some help here.
- Right. Okay.
중요한건 어떤 거짓말이냐가 아니라
어떻게 거짓말 하느냐야
So it's not just the lie you tell,
but it's the way you tell it. For example..
말하면서 아래를 쳐다보면
거짓말이란게 들통나
if you look at the ground when
you talk, people know you're lying.
왜 이렇게 힘들지?
거짓말도 연기고
I don't know why this is so hard for me.
Lying is basically just acting..
- 난 훌륭한 배우인데 말야
- 맞아, 훌륭한 배우지
- and I am a terrific actor.
- You are a terrific actor.
내가 PD한테 얘기해 줄까?
내가 거짓말엔 일인자잖아
I could talk to the producers for you.
I'm a great liar.
예를 들어, 내가 모니카
드레스를 보고 멋지다고 했는데
Take Monica's dress. I said I loved it.
- 실은, 되게 촌스럽거든
- 뭐라구?
- I hate it.
- Hey!
사람들은 나를 바보라고도 하지
I'm also a great moron.
- 애는 어디 있어?
- 방금 재웠어
- Hey. Where's the baby?
- We just put her down for a nap.
생각해봤는데..
정말 근사할것 같지 않아?
Listen, I was just thinking.
You know what would be incredible?
두사람이 죽으면 말야!
If you guys died!
고마워, 에이미
Thank you, Amy.
그러면 내가 엠마를 맡게 돼
No, no, then I would get the baby.
영화 같을거야!
처음엔 어쩔줄 몰라 허둥대다가
It would be just like a movie. At first
I wouldn't know what to do with her.
결국 난관을 헤쳐나가겠지
And then I would rise to the occasion.
Then I'd get a makeover and get married.
내 인생은 완전히 바뀌고
결혼하게 될거야!
멋진 영화네요!
That's a great movie!
어차피 두사람은
죽었을 테니까
Now, listen, not that you guys
could stop me or anything..
날 말릴수도 없겠지만..
because you know, you'd be dead.
애 이름 바꿀까봐
But I was thinking about
changing her name.
에밀리란 이름 너무 별로야
I'm just not really a big fan of Emily.
엠마!
Emma.
엠마, 로스가 불러요
Emma? Ross wants you.
피비!
Phoebe!
왜 자꾸 저런 이상한
소리를 내는거지?
Why does she keep making that noise?
어떻게 말해야 할지
모르겠는데
Honey, I don't know
how to tell you this..
만약 우리한테
무슨일 생기면..
but if something were to happen
to Ross or myself..
- 너한테는 애 안맡길거야
- 그럼 누구 줄건데?
- you wouldn't get the baby.
- Well, who would?
정식으로 부탁한 적은 없지만
Well, we haven't officially
asked them yet..
모니카와 챈들러한테
맡기고 싶어
but we would want
Monica and Chandler.
- 누구?
- 이 아파트 주인이잖아
- Who?
- You're in their apartment.
이럴수가! 우리한테
엠마를 맡기겠다구?
I can't believe you'd want us
to raise Emma.
어쩜, 나 감동받았어!
Oh, my God, I'm so moved.
뭐가 어째?
두사람 죽어도
I don't believe this. Hold on a second.
You guys die..
나한테 애 안맡긴다구?
and I don't get your baby?
우린 모니카 부부와
훨씬 더 친해
Amy, see, we're a lot closer
to Monica and Chandler.
매일보는 사이라구, 솔직히 넌
우리 엠마한테 별로 정도 없잖아
We see them every day. And truthfully,
you don't seem connected to the baby.
주먹만한 살덩이한테
정은 무슨 정?!
Connected? To what? She's a lump.
나한테 지금 그말이 얼마나
의미깊고 소중한지 몰라
You know, guys, I've gotta say
this means so much to me.
아이를 맡길 정도로
날 믿는다는 거잖아
I mean, that you would
trust me with your child.
다들 알다시피 우리 부부
I mean, we all know
that Monica and I have been..
아이 가지려고 노력중이고..
trying to have a baby of our own.
내가 아빠로서 자격이 있는지
확신은 없지만..
You know, I've had my doubts
about my skills as a father, but..
너희 둘..
That you two..
- 정말..
- 이런 사람한테 맡긴다구?
- That you two..
- This guy?
진심이야?
Seriously?
저녁 다 준비됐어요!
Okay, it's time for dinner.
오늘 특별히
예쁜 그릇을 준비했습니다
Everyone, we're using our fancy china..
아주 비싼 거니까
부디 조심해주세요
and it's very expensive,
so please be careful.
접시 가지고 장난치면
신상에 해로울 테니 명심하시길!
Okay, just to be clear, comedy with
the plates will not be well-received.
뭐야!
Hey!
내 접시는 왜
다른 애들 것보다 안 예뻐?
How come my plate's less fancy
than everyone else's?
내가 비싼거 깰까봐 그래?
Do you not trust me with a fancy plate?
아냐, 그건 특별 접시야
No, honey. That's a special plate.
게임하는 거야
그 접시 주인이 이기는 거지
See, it's a game.
Whoever gets that plate wins.
그럼 내가 이긴거네!
I can't believe I won!
이건 모욕이야!
동생인 날 두고
You know, this is such a slap
in the face. I mean, I'm your sister..
생판 모르는
남한테 애를 맡긴다구?
and you would give your baby
to these strangers over me.
모니카는 로스 동생이야
Monica is Ross' sister.
아냐, 로스 동생은 뚱땡이였어!
No, Ross' sister was really fat.
그게 나야
That was me.
아니, 모니카는 울 언니 뒤를 졸졸
쫓아다니던 아주 멍청한 애였어요!
No, she was this dorky girl in school
who followed Rachel around like a puppy..
너 정말 입 안다물래?!
Amy, you've got to stop doing that!
가족간의 불화는 이해하지만
Okay, listen, I know you're having
a bit of a family crisis..
접시에 화풀이하진 말아줘
but you don't have to take it out
on the plates.
그리고 모두들..
I mean, in fact, I think that everyone..
음식을 이렇게 썰어 먹도록 해
should cut their food like this:
봤지?
이러면 접시도 보호하고
Now, see? This way,
you protect the plates..
재미도 있어
and let's face it, you have fun.
이건 어때?
만약 두사람 죽고
Okay, how about this?
If you guys die..
이 싸이코 아줌마까지 죽고나면
and the crazy plate lady dies..
- 그땐 애 나 주는거야?
- 아뇨, 이 싸이코 아줌마까지..
- then do I get the baby?
- No, if crazy plate lady..
모니카가 죽으면
내가 엠마를 키우게 돼요, 그렇지?
If Monica dies,
then I would get Emma. Right?
- 사실은..
- 사실은.. 뭐?
- Well, actually..
- Actually what?
만약 그런일이 생기면
It's just..
It's just that in that case..
우리 부모님한테 맡길거야
then Emma would go to my parents.
- 뭐?
- 열받죠?
- What?
- Hurts, doesn't it?
내가 아기 가지려면
누가 죽어야해?
Who has to die for me to get her?
모니카 없이 나 혼자선
엠마 키울 자격이 없어?
So if Monica's not around,
I'm not good enough to raise Emma?
그런뜻이 아냐
No, that is not what we're saying.
거짓말이야
아래를 보고 말하잖아
Yeah, he's lying. He looked down.
내가 어때서?
무능력하다는 거야?
Well, what's wrong with me?
Am I incompetent?
너희 셋 죽을 동안에도
살아남을 나란 말야!
Because I managed to survive whatever
it is that killed the three of you!
오해하지마, 넌 훌륭한 아빠가
될거라고 생각해
You're taking this the wrong way. We think
you are going to be a wonderful parent.
다만 넌좀
'재미있는 아빠'일 가능성이 커
It's just.. You're more the,
you know, fun parent.
그래서 엠마에겐 모니카 같은
사람도 옆에 있으면 좋겠어
Yeah, and we wanna make sure
Emma also has someone like Monica..
엄한 사람 말야
who's more of a disciplinarian.
줏대있고 깐깐한 사람
Someone who can be firm and strict.
내가 그렇다는 뜻이야?
That's not how you see me, is it?
아냐, 너도 재미있는 사람이야
No, you're all about the fun.
육아에 대해 잘은 모르지만
내가 정말 능력이 안돼?
I may not know a lot about babies,
but do you really think I'm not capable?
둘다 능력있지만
No. You both are equally capable.
둘이 함께일때
효과가 제일 크다는 거야
It's just you're strongest
when you're together.
그럼 우리가 엠마를 키우다가
내가 죽으면
Okay. So if we both had Emma,
and I died..
모니카도 엠마 포기해야겠네?
she'd have to give her up.
물론이지
모니카도 엠마를 포기해야지
Sure. Monica would have to give her up.
내가 거짓말해도
저것보단 잘하겠다, 그치?
I lie better than that, right?
그럼 정리해보자, 내 소중한
두 친구가 죽으면 난 엠마를 맡게돼
Let me just get this straight.
So my two friends die, I get Emma.
그런데 마누라까지 죽으면
유일한 삶의 희망일 엠마를
Then my wife dies. Then Emma,
the one tiny ray of hope left in my life..
- 뺏어간다구?
- 멋진 한편의 영화다!
- gets taken away from me?
- There's your movie.
여기 있었어?
Hey, there you are.
- 밥먹고 안보이더니
- 누가 나 찾아?
- You disappeared after dinner.
- Did somebody miss me?
어떤 아기가
자격없는 아빠 필요하대?
Was there a child to raise poorly?
오빠랑 레이첼은
잘모르고 한 얘기야
Ross and Rachel don't know
what they're saying.
자기들은 뭐 그렇게
책임감이 많나?
It's not like they're so responsible.
엠마는 포도주 1병과
5년 묵은 콘돔이 빚은 산물인걸
Emma is a product of a bottle of merlot
and a five-year-old condom.
틀린 말도 아니지, 난 절대로
강한 아빠가 될수 없을거야
No, but they're right. I'm not a strong
father figure, and I never will be.
그건 배워 가는거야
좋은 아빠가 돼가고 있는걸
No, you learn these things.
You grow into it.
하지만 내 본성이 그렇잖아
Yeah, but it's not who I am.
아까 걔들 말한거
내가 걱정했던것 그대로라구
Everything they said is exactly why I was
worried about having a kid. And it's true.
봐, 내가 모자라다는걸
모두들 알고 있다구
- And look, everybody knows it.
- I don't know it.
난 모르겠는데?
난 자기가 멋진 아빠가 될거라고
믿기 때문에 아기 낳고 싶은거야
I wanna have a kid with you because
I think you'll be an amazing dad.
'재미있는 아빠'와
'엄한 아빠' 모두 다
At the fun parts and at the hard parts.
내가 이러는거 상상이 가?
"방에 들어가! 외출금지야!"
Well, can you picture me saying,
"Go to your room, you're grounded"?
내가 그러는건 상상이 돼?
Can you hear me say,
"You're grounded"?
지난주에 나한테 그랬잖아
You said that to me last week.
가구에 발 올려놓지 말라는게
뭐 그렇게 어려워?
How hard is it?
"No shoes on the furniture!"
PD가 퍼레이드에 왜
안나왔냐고 메시지 남겼어
The producer from Days left a message
asking why I wasn't at the parade.
다들 나한테 화났대!
그리고 산타클로스 보러갔대!
They said everybody's really pissed off
at me. And they all got to meet Santa!
널 위해
완벽한 거짓말을 준비했어
It's okay.
I thought of the perfect lie for you.
기억하기도 쉽고
이런 저런 질문받을 일도 없어
It's easy to remember,
and it doesn't invite a lot of questions.
우주선과 관계된 거구나?
Does it have something to do
with a spaceship?
아님, 자유의 여신상이
살아나서..
The Statue of Liberty came to life..
집안에 급한일이 생겨서
퍼레이드에 못갔다고 해
You weren't at the parade
because you had a family emergency.
그거 좋다!
I like that! Yeah!
집안에 급한일이 생겨서
퍼레이드에 못갔어요
I wasn't at the parade
because I had a family emergency.
저런, 무슨 일인데?
What happened?
- 여동생의 너구리가..
- 제발 너구리좀 빼!
- My sister's raccoon came..
- No, nothing with a raccoon!
- 뭐하는 거야?
- 그릇 놓잖아
- Wait, what are you doing?
- Setting the table.
후식 먹을때도 예쁜 그릇 쓰면
좋을것 같아서
We thought it might be nice
to use the fancy china for dessert too.
좋기도 하겠다, 다음엔 내
웨딩드레스에 코풀자고 하겠구나
How nice. Maybe later we can all go
blow our noses on my wedding dress.
챈들러, 아까 일은 미안해
Hey, dude, you okay?
Sorry about before.
괜찮아, 너희 말이 맞아
내가 어떻게 애를 잘 키우겠니?
That's okay. You're totally right. I don't
know anything about disciplining a child.
하지만 속은 상해
만약 나 죽으면
But it did hurt my feelings,
and I want you to know that if I die..
너한테 조이 안맡길거야
you don't get Joey.
눈치 못챘을까봐 말해주는데
나 언니랑 말 안할거야!
In case you hadn't noticed,
I'm not talking to you.
정말 언니다운 발상이야!
You know, this is just..
This is classic Rachel.
맞아! 고등학교때 나 죽었을 때도
너한테 애 안맡겼던거 기억하지?
Oh, yeah, right. Remember in high school
when I died and didn't give you my baby?
내가 아기를 가질수 있는
유일한 기회일지도 몰라
This might be my one chance
to have a child, Rachel.
알다시피 난 일 때문에
너무 바빠서..
I mean, you know that I have been
so busy focusing on my career..
- 일? 무슨일?
- 나 인테리어 디자이너야!
- What career?
- I'm a decorator.
아빠 사무실 한번 꾸미고
인테리어 디자이너라구?
You decorate Dad's office
and now you're a decorator?
나 어제 동물원 다녀왔어
이제부터 난 코알라야
Okay, I went to the zoo yesterday,
now I'm a koala bear.
- 나좀 밀어주면 안돼?
- 뭐? 지금 밀어달라고 했니?
- Why can't you ever be supportive?
- You wanna talk supportive?
내가 애낳고 병원에 있을때
넌 코빼기도 안비쳤던 애야!
You didn't come and visit me when
I was in the hospital having the baby!
언니도 나 입술 수술해서
입원했을 때 안와봤잖아!
You didn't come see me in the hospital
when I was getting my lips done!
첫번째 수술했을땐 갔어!
I did the first time.
내가 왜 너한테 우리 에밀리
안맡기려는줄 알아?
You know what? You wanna know
why I am not giving Emily to you?
- 엠마
- 자긴 대체 누구 편이야?!
- Emma.
- Whose side are you on?!
그건 네가 애를 키울만한
책임감이 없기 때문이야!
I'm not giving you Emma because you
can't handle the responsibility of a child.
애 키우는게 뭐 힘들어?
언니도 하잖아!
Well, how hard could it be?
You do it.
언니가 왜 나한테 애
안맡기려는줄 알아?
You wanna know why
you don't want me to have the baby?
내가 행복해지는게 싫어서야
Because you don't want me to be happy.
- 언니는 언제나 날 시샘했어!
- 뭘 시샘해?
- You have always been jealous of me.
- Jealous of what?
너 무책임한거?
철없는거?
Of your lack of responsibility?
Your immaturity?
아니면 다른사람 감정
요만큼도 생각 안하는거?
Your total disregard
for other people's feelings?
내가 언제? 이름 대봐!
To name a few.
언니는 늘 이런 식이었어
You've always been like this.
자긴 모든걸 다 가져야 하고
난 아무것도 가지면 안되지
You had to have everything,
and I couldn't have anything.
고등학교때
티미도 뺏어갔잖아!
Like in junior high,
when you stole Timmy from me.
얼마나 분통 터졌는줄 알아?
I mean, do you even realize
how much that hurt me?
티미는 내 남자친구였어!
네가 걔 꼬신 거잖아!
Timmy was my boyfriend,
and you made out with him!
20년이나 지난 일이야!
그만좀 잊어!
Come on, that was 20 years ago.
Get over it.
오늘 널 여기 초대하다니
내가 미쳤지!
I cannot believe
that I invited you here today!
기가 막힌건 나야!
언니라는 인간은
Yeah, well, you know what I cannot
believe? That my so-called sister..
랄프 로렌에서 30% 할인 받는데
난 제값 다 내야해?
gets a 30 percent discount from Ralph
Lauren, and I still have to pay retail?
45% 할인이다!
It's 45.
못됐어!
You bitch.
애랑 코딱지 만한
You just think you're so perfect..
집에서 사니까
세상이 다 언니것 같지?
with your new baby
and your small apartment.
솔직히 말해줄까?
언니 애기 못생겼어!
Well, let me tell you something.
Your baby isn't even that cute.
그말은 너무 심해, 에이미!
Too far, Amy. Too far.
- 그말 취소해
- 싫어!
- You take that back.
- No.
- 취소해!
- 싫어!
- Take it back!
- No. What are you gonna do? Make me?
어쩔건데?
힘으로 해보려구?
조심해
나 요즘 운동한다!
Hey, man, I work out!
- 나두 해
- 난 필라테스 해!
- So do I.
- I do Pilates.
- 난 요가 해!
- 덤벼!
- I do yoga.
- Bring it on!
접시 상자에 집어넣어!
어서 집어넣어!
Put the plates in the boxes!
- 날 밀었어?
- 밀었다, 어쩔래?
- Did you just push me?
- Yeah, I think I did.
좋아! 너 죽었어!
All right, that's it.
비닐 포장지는 둬!
그럴시간 없어!
Forget the bubble wrap!
There isn't time!
이 부슬부슬 곱슬머리야!
Frizzy, frizzy, frizzy!
- 말려야 하는것 아냐?
- 무슨 소리야!
- Shouldn't we stop this?
- Are you out of your mind?
쟤들한테 젤리도 던지자!
Let's throw some Jell-O on them!
저러다 누구 다치겠어
Hey, someone could get hurt.
발로 차, 레이첼!
발로 차!
Kick her, Rach! Kick her!
웃도리를 벗겨, 레이첼!
웃도리를 벗겨!
Pull her top off, Rach! Pull her top off!
더러워!
Gross!
그만해! 여긴 우리 집이야!
이게 무슨 짓이야!
All right, that is it! This is our apartment,
and you cannot behave this way!
나이값 할 자신 없으면
다들 여기서 나가
If you can't act your age,
you shouldn't be here at all.
이 접시 내가 골랐던 분홍색만큼
예쁘지 않을진 모르지만
Those plates may not be as nice as
the pretty pink ones that I picked out..
모니카에겐 아주 소중한 거야
둘다 모니카에게 사과해!
but they're important to Monica.
And I want you to apologize to her, now.
- 미안해요
- 정말 미안해, 모니카
- I'm sorry.
- Mon, I'm so sorry.
훨씬 좋군
Okay. That's better.
이제 서로 진심으로 화해해
Now, I want you to apologize
to each other and mean it.
- 미안해
- 미안
- Sorry.
그나저나 방금 싸운거
아주 멋있었어!
By the way, that fight
was totally arousing.
아주 잘했어!
Dude, well done.
나랑 레이첼 죽고, 모니카도 죽으면
너한테 엠마 맡겨도 문제없겠다
If I die and Rachel dies and Monica dies,
you can totally take care of Emma.
정말? 고마워
Yeah? Well, thanks.
그럼 이제
조이 나한테 맡길거지?
So..
So now do I get Joey?
하루 다섯끼 먹고 걸핏하면
콧구멍에 동전 넣는 애니까 잘해봐
Okay. But you should know he eats a lot
and shoves pennies up his nose.
- 괜찮니?
- 그럼
Are you okay, Mon?
이럴수도 있지
그냥 접시일 뿐인걸
I mean, these things happen.
I mean, it's just a plate.
- 누가 죽은것도 아니잖아
- 괜찮아, 실컷 울어
- It's not like somebody died.
- It's all right. You can mourn.
고마워!
정말 예쁜 그릇이었는데!
Thank you. It was so beautiful!
조이네 가서 파이 가져올게
I'm gonna go to Joey's
and get the pies.
실은 파이 한개밖에 안남았어
Actually, not pies. It's just pie.
상관없어
I don't care.
맙소사! 잔소리 할
의욕마저 사라졌어!
Oh, my God, I've lost the will to scold.
에이미
Look, Amy..
아깐 우리 둘다
we got a little..
이성을 잃었던것 같아
a little out-of-control over there.
미안하다
And I'm sorry.
넌 내 동생이야
You're my sister..
그게 너한테
그렇게 중요하다면..
and if it really means
that much to you..
- 아기 나한테 맡길거야?
- 아니
- So you're gonna give me the baby?
- No, I was..
랄프 로렌
할인받게 해준다구
I was gonna let you use
my Ralph Lauren discount.
절대 후회 안할거야!
You are not gonna regret this.
- 기저귀 갈아야 하나봐
- 아냐, 내가 할게
- She needs changing.
- No, no, no. I'll get her.
자신감과 책임감 넘치고
엠마 양육서열 4위인 내가 하겠어!
I am super confident, totally responsible
and fourth in line to raise Emma.
기다려, 엠마! 믿음직한
기저귀 가방 들고 금방 갈게
I'll be right there, Emma! Just let me
get my trusty diaper bag here.
누가 알아? 내가 제일 먼저
죽을지도 모르지
Well, what do you know?
I guess I'll be the one who dies first.
- 접시 깨진거 모니카는 아직 몰라?
- 몰라
- Does Monica know about her plates?
- Nope.
- 몽땅 깨진거야?
- 그래
- Broke them all, huh?
- Yep.
- 말할거야?
- 아니
- You gonna tell her?
- Nope.
접시 제자리에 올려 놓을게
Hey. So I'm gonna
put the plates back.
자기 말이 맞아, 앞으로 한동안은
이 접시 꺼내 쓰지말자
I think you're right. We shouldn't
use these plates for a long time.
- 여왕이 오셨을 때만 빼고?
- 그때도 쓰지마
- Like only if the queen comes?
- Maybe not even then.
성공이야!
Hey. I did it.
PD한테 걸어서 급한 집안 일이
있었다고 했더니 믿더라구!
I told my producer I had a family
emergency. He totally bought it.
- 거짓말하는 법 가르쳐줘서 고마워
- 다음주엔 도둑질 가르쳐줄게
- Thanks for teaching me how to lie.
- No problem. Next week, stealing.
- 안녕, 예쁜 접시들아
- 접시 왕창 박살낸거 얘기했구나?
- Bye, plates.
- You told her you broke all the plates?
뭐?
접시가 어떻게 됐다구?
What?!
Something happened with the plates?
어..
너구리가 들어와서 말야..
Yeah, this raccoon came in..